Finding Aid for William Pollard papers, 1961-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William Pollard papers 1961-1995, 1972-1983
Pollard, William.
3 linear feet
97137 Aa 2
Member of the Ann Arbor Airport Advisory Committee; collected materials detailing operation of the airport and dispute over the proposed airport expansion.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection was received through Ms. Eloise Pollard (donor no. 6415 ) in October 1997.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
William Pollard was a longtime member of the Ann Arbor Airport Advisory Committee and an outspoken critic of attempts to expand the Ann Arbor airport. The Ann Arbor Municipal Airport, located near the intersection of State Street and Ellsworth Road in south Ann Arbor, was built in 1928 surrounded by what was then farmland. By the 1970s nearby suburban development was causing the airport to become a subject of extreme controversy. Some parts of the community wanted to expand the airport to allow for larger planes and night landings. Other members of the community wanted to keep it as it was or even close the airport and sell the valuable real estate. Several proposals to expand the airport were made but the Ann Arbor City Council, Washtenaw Planning Commission and the Airport Advisory Committee did not approve these plans although improvements were made to the airport following World War II and in 1977. In 1993, the City Council rejected a plan to sell the airport to a regional authority, which would have led to a loss of control over plans to expand the airport.
The William Pollard collection consists of his accumulation of material relating to his interest in the Ann Arbor Municipal Airport. This collection is divided into four series: Advisory Committee, Expansion, Legislation and Regulation and Topical Files.
Subjects:
Pollard, William.; Airports--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor Airport Advisory Committee.
- Advisory Committee
  The Advisory Committee is the body which oversees the running of the airport for the Ann Arbor City Council. The series spans the years 1972 to 1995. It contains the minutes of committee meetings, resolutions and material relating to issues discussed at the meetings. The expansion of the airport was the largest issue the committee had to deal with so there is some material which complements the Expansion series.
  - 1972-1995, 14 folders (Box 1)
- Expansion 1972-1995
  The Expansion series covers the years 1972-1995. It includes material from the Ann Arbor City Council and Washtenaw County Planning Commission as well as citizens groups. The series details several attempts to expand the airport by lengthening the runway and establishing an instrument landing system about which there was heavy opposition. The bulk of the material comes from the expansion efforts in 1975 and 1979.
  - Ann Arbor Aviation Association 1979 (Box 1)
  - Citizens Association for Area Planning 1979 (Box 1)
  - City Council and Washtenaw County Planning Commission
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - 1979, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1983-1995 (Box 1)
  - Clippings
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1991 (Box 1)
  - Community Review Team 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1972-1975 (Box 2)
    - 1976 (Box 2)
    - 1979 (Box 2)
  - Financial Reports 1975-1979 (Box 2)
  - Master Plan, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Realignment and Extension 1983 (Box 2)
  - South Ann Arbor Council 1979 (Box 2)
- Legislation and Regulations 1967-1991
  The Legislation and Regulations series dates from 1967 to 1991. It includes material from the local, state and federal governments regarding airport laws and regulation. Most of the material was issued by the Federal Aviation Administration.
  - Federal
    - 1974-1983, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Local 1976-1981 (Box 2)
  - Michigan 1967-1975 (Box 2)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series contains material from 1961 to 1993. It includes various reports, grants and clippings dealing with the Ann Arbor Airport. There is also some information about other airports in the area such as Detroit Metro and Willow Run.
  - Airport Manager's Report 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Budget
    - 1965-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975-1990 (Box 2)
  - Clippings
    - 1961-1993 (Box 2)
    - Notebook 1988-1995, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Detroit Metro (Romulus) 1988 (Box 3)
  - Grants 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Maps of Airport 1976-1982, undated (Box 3)
  - Mettelal Airport, (Canton) 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Aviation, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Aviation System Plan, General Aviation Facilities 1990-2010, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Department of Transportation Reports 1992 (Box 3)
  - National Airport System Plan 1978-1987, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Noise
    - Compatibility Study 1991, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Federal Aviation Administration 1975 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1976-1977 (Box 3)
      - 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Southeastern Michigan Council of Governments Reports 1992 (Box 3)
  - State Airport Plans 1970-1990 (Box 3)
  - Tenant Information 1974-1979 (Box 3)
  - Tenant Strike 1992-1993, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Willow Run (Ypsilanti) 1975-1979 (Box 3)